(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-09-27T12:48:23.742767",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, shining bright!
呼び合う声を合図に
At the signal of our calling voices.
パレード パレード パレード
Parade, parade, parade,
探しに行く
off to go search
スタートはなんとなくだって
even if the start was just on a whim.
ただ独りごとつぶやいた
I simply murmured to myself.
ただ始まりたくて走った
I ran because I just wanted it to begin.
遠く暗がりに凍った
Frozen in the distant gloom,
それは眩しすぎた名前
that name was much too dazzling.
それは優しすぎる思い出
That memory was far too gentle.
もっと近づけと手を伸ばした 思いがけず結びあった
I reached out to get closer, and unexpectedly we connected.
ほら今迷子は僕らになった
Look, now we've become the lost ones.
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright!
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
Bring along both your regrets and your affection.
風 夢 晴れ 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, clear skies—we can take flight!
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
A modest prayer is a light, a sign without end.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張るよ
I'll hold my head high that I found you.
ここから これから あわい パレード パレード
From here, from now on, in the faint light, parade, parade!
まだ頼りない予感を
Still holding onto this uncertain premonition,
歌を恥ずかしくなんてないよ
there's nothing to be embarrassed about in singing.
誰も解けないイマジナリー
An imaginary thing nobody can solve,
いつかまた会えるおまじない
a spell to meet again someday.
あの日ゼロに始まったストーリー
The story that began at zero on that day—
数え切れないこと数えるような思い出じゃないさ
it's not just a memory of counting countless things.
ほら今僕らを一つと呼ぼう
Look, let's call ourselves one right now.
パレード パレード パレード 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, it's so beautiful!
許し合える切な夜はきらめく
Nights of bittersweet forgiveness sparkle.
雨 晴れ 晴れ またとない空
Rain, clear skies, clear skies—a sky like no other.
ふさわしい日々とは君とあることさ
Days worthy of us mean being here with you.
君とあることなんだ ただ今を聴けば
It means being with you... If you listen right now,
おかえりって叫ぶよ
I will shout out, "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't it obvious?
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright!
暗がりを満たすのは君だ 僕だ
What fills the darkness is you, it's me!
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright!
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
Bring along both your regrets and your affection.
風 夢 晴れ 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, clear skies—we can take flight!
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
A modest prayer is a light, a sign without end.
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in together with you—what a wonderful start!
ここから これから あわい パレード パレード
From here, from now on, in the faint light, parade, parade!
あわい パレード パレード
In the faint light, parade, parade!
と言うことで、ロザミア アコースティックライブ始まりましたーー！
And with that, RosaMiA Acoustic Live has begun!
イエーイ！
Yay!
どうでしたかーー？
How was it?!
いやー1曲目からね、アコースティックのパレードとか、なんかさ、こういう感じでこの曲歌ったことなかったからさ、すごいドキドキしちゃった。
Man, starting right off with the acoustic version of "Parade"... we've never sung this song in this kind of vibe before, so my heart was pounding.
めちゃめちゃ分かる。
I totally get it.
賛成になってましたね。
We were totally in sync.
はい。
Yeah.
なんか最後ポーズ決めるの忘れたりちょっとね。集中しすぎて、歌に集中しすぎてちょっと忘れちゃったかも。
And you know, at the very end we almost forgot to hold our poses... We were just so focused on singing, maybe we forgot a bit.
まぁ、そんなこともありながらね！はい！
Well, things like that happen too! Yeah!
あ、もうすでに、え？
Ah, already? Huh?
なんと、え、こちら
And, um, here...
ハッシュタグのトレンドで、え、3位に入ってるらしい！
It seems we're already #3 in the hashtag trends!
何！？すごい！
What?! That's amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
あ、とりあえずちょっと自己紹介から、から、自己紹介しましょう。
Ah, first let's start with self-introductions.
笑いましょうかね、はい。
Let's laugh, yeah.
じゃあちょっと、よろしくお願いします。
Well then, nice to meet you.
では、自己紹介させていただきます。
Now, allow me to introduce myself.
え、ローザミアのローザ・タント、アキロゼことアキロゼスタータスです。
Um, RosaMiA's Rosa Tant, Aki Rose aka Aki Rosenthal.
はろはろはろ、アロナ！
Hello hello hello, Arona!
そして、はい！
And, yes!
ローザミアのミータンと、長女の狼ミオです。
RosaMiA's Mī-tan, and the eldest sister, Ookami Mio.
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
そして、はい！
And, yes!
ローザミアのアータンと、末っ子の月見亜子です。
RosaMiA's Ā-tan, and the youngest, Tsukimi Azuki.
月見亜子です、よろしくお願いします。
Tsukimi Azuki, nice to meet you.
なんか、息生きとさ、すわえっこしてるんだよね、なんかこの空間にいると。
It feels so vibrant being in this space.
こうね、すっきりでいられる。
Being able to feel refreshed like this...
の、幸せです、ありがとうございます。
...is such happiness, thank you.
すぐだ、すぐじゃ。
Right away, right away.
長女、す、あ、次女、すえっ、あ、次女、すえっ子でやらせていただい...
As the second daughter, youngest...
三姉妹でやらせていただいております。
...we are doing this as three sisters.
はい、ということでね、この3人でローザミアというグループをやらせていただいているんですけれども。
Yes, so with these three, we are doing a group called RosaMiA.
なんとですね、このローザミアでライブをするのは今回初めてということで。
And surprisingly, doing a live as RosaMiA is a first for us.
しかも、あの生歌唱のライブということでね。
And furthermore, it's an all-live vocal concert.
3人でいっぱい練習しましたね。
The three of us practiced a lot.
練習しました。合宿のように。
We practiced, like a training camp.
頑張ったね、部活みたいでさ、楽しく。
We worked hard, like club activities, and it was fun.
部活だ、合勝部みたいな感じでね。
It was like a chorus club.
たくさん練習したのでね、たくさん練習した1曲目どうでしたでしょうか？
How was the first song we practiced so much?
どうでした？いや、一番難しいまであるか？
How was it? No, is it perhaps the most difficult one?
いや、そんなことはない、そんなことはない。
No, it's not that much.
そんなことはなかった。でもかなり難しい方ではあった。
It wasn't like that. But it was quite difficult.
そうだね。
That's right.
パート分けでしたよね。
It was divided into parts, right?
いや、そうかね、パート分けが難しかったかも。
Yeah, maybe dividing the parts was difficult.
そうそうそう。というわけで、トレンドが3位にも入っているという情報ですが。
Right. So, we heard the hashtag is trending at #3.
はい、ハッシュタグこちらとなっております！
Yes, here is the hashtag!
#ローザミアアコースティックライブ というタグで、皆さんどしどしXでポストをしてくださいね！
Please post on X with the tag #RosaMiA_Acoustic_Live!
あとで、あのエゴサするので。
Later on, we'll be checking social media.
頑張ったのでね、応援だったりとか感想とか。
We worked hard, so cheering messages and impressions...
わかる！つけていっぱいね、盛り上げてくれたら嬉しい。
...I get it! We'd be happy if you hype it up a lot.
知らない人にも届けたいですよね。
We want to reach people who don't know us yet, right?
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
今2位になってるよって。
They say we're at #2 right now.
え！？すごすぎる！
What?! That's amazing!
ありがとうございます！ぜひぜひいっぱいポストしてね。
Thank you very much! Please post a lot.
っていうことでですね。
So, uh...
え、どんどんいっちゃうんですか、これ？それとも永遠にここでトークしてるんですか？
Wait, are we moving on already? Or talking forever?
え、ちょっとさ、お水の中...
Um, like, in the water...
ちょっと一瞬のお水を、一緒に、一緒にの、の、飲ませてくださいね。
Let us take a quick sip of water together, please.
お水美味しい、美味しい。
Water is delicious, delicious.
いや、一緒にお水のまさて下さいとか言いつつ、そろそろ次の曲いっちゃいますか？
Should we move on to the next song soon?
いっちゃいますか？
Shall we go?
いっちゃいます？
Shall we?
はい、というわけで次の曲は、うちとあきちゃんの二人ということ で、こっから二人ずつ歌っていくんですね。
Yes, the next song is with Uchi and Aki-chan, singing in pairs.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
じゃあ、二人手準備お願いします。
Well then, you two, please get ready.
あずちゃんもね、お水飲んでもらったところ恐縮なんですけれども。
Az-chan, sorry after you just drank water, but...
あのMCを、二人をね、今ね準備しておりますので。
...we are preparing the MC for the two of you right now.
はーい、みんな！ローザミアのアコースティックライブ来てくれてありがとー！
Hii, everyone! Thank you for coming to RosaMiA's acoustic live!
1曲目いかがでしたか？
How was the first song?
Our Bright Parade、今回ね、ぜひアレンジにも注目していただきたいなと、ちょっといつもと違う、おしゃれなアレンジになっておりますので。
Please pay attention to the stylish arrangement of Our Bright Parade.
そこもね、それと合わせて3人のハーモニーを聞いていただけたらなと思います。
We hope you can listen to our three-part harmony.
というところで、二人手準備できたみたいなので。
So, it seems the two of them are ready.
はい。
Yes.
はい、聞いていただきましょう。ジェン・ドゥ。
Yes, please listen to it. JANE DOE.
まるでこの世界で二人だけみたいだね
It's almost as if we're the only two people in this world,
なんて少しだけ夢を見てしまっただけ
Or so I briefly dreamed for just a moment.
つま先に月明かり 花束の香り 指に触れる指
Moonlight on my toes, the scent of a bouquet, fingers touching fingers.
さようなら もう行かなくちゃ 何もかも忘れて
Goodbye, I have to go now, forgetting everything.
硝子の年を裸足のままで歩く 痛むたびに血が流れ落ちていく
Walking barefoot across glass, bleeding with every step of pain.
お願い その赤い足跡を辿って 会いにきて
I beg you, follow those red footprints and come meet me.
忘れて...
Forget...
ガラスの上を 裸足のまま歩く
Walking barefoot on glass,
痛むことに 血が流れて落ちていく
blood flows and drips as it hurts.
お願い その赤い足跡を辿って 会いに来て
Please, follow those red footprints and come meet me.
錆びたプールに 放たれてく金曜
Released into the rusted pool on Friday,
靴箱の中 隠したリンゴ
the apple hidden inside the shoe locker,
錆びた君の肌に 残る傷あとは
the lingering scars on your rusted skin,
どこにいるの様に 泳いだ迷子
like where could you be, swimming as a lost child.
どこに どこにいるよ
Where, where are you?
何をしても 見てるよ
What are you doing? I'm watching you.
この世をまちがいで満たそう
Let's fill this world with mistakes,
そばにいてよ 遊びにいこうよ どこに眠るの
stay by my side, where do you sleep?
ガラスの上を 裸足のまま歩く
Walking barefoot on glass,
痛むことに 血が流れて落ちていく
blood flows and drips as it hurts.
お願い その赤い足跡を辿って 会いに来て
Please, follow those red footprints and come meet me.
会いに来て
Come meet me.
まるでこの世界で 二人だけみたいだね
It's as if we're the only two in this world,
なんて少しだけ 夢を見てしまっただけ
just dreaming a little bit, that's all.
はーい、歌い切った！
Yay, we sang it through!
いや、やっぱ素敵な曲だね、本当だね。
Man, what a wonderful song.
というわけで、あきちゃんとうちのジェーンででした！
So that was Aki-chan and our Jane Doe!
めちゃくちゃ素敵！
Absolutely wonderful!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
あー、ちょっと緊張した。緊張した！
I got a little nervous.
あんなこと感じさせない歌声でしたよ、本当に本当に。
Nervous! You wouldn't guess that from your singing voice.
本当によかった。
Really, really?
よかった！
I'm glad.
なんか、ね、なんかこの曲は、ま、二人づね、これから歌っていくんだろみたいな、うっすら思ってるかもしれないんですけど
You might vaguely think, "Ah, the two of us will be singing this from now on,"
え、どうですか？どこが難しかったですか？この曲は。
but um, how was it? Where was it difficult, this song?
え、でもやっぱハモリがさ、原曲より少し多めにこうハモる場所を作ってて
Um, well, the harmonies have a bit more places where we harmonize than the original song,
確かに。で、そこのやっぱ掛け合いとかこう合わせるみたいなのとかを、あの、呼吸感とか。
exactly. And things like the interplay and matching each other, um, the sense of breathing.
あ、でもね、あの、あきちゃんが多分子前、あの、あきちゃんのライブでジェーンやってるからかわかんないけど、ほぼ完璧だったわけ。
Ah, but you know, Aki-chan probably had done Jane in her live show before, so she was almost perfection right from the start.
いやいや、そんなことないよ！最初から激うまだったって！練習しなきゃいけないのウチだったわけ！
No way, not at all! It was super good from the start! We were the ones who had to practice!
ウチだったわけ？アキロゼのセーターサイズで、あの
You were? In Akirose's sweater size...
みおちゃんパートのメロディを歌わせてもらったことがあって
I'd had the chance to sing Mio-chan's part melody before,
こっちのあのユネズさんパートは、あ、じゃ初調整だったんだけど、雰囲気とかはね。
and this Yunezu-san part, ah, it was my first time trying it, but the vibe and all,
いや分かってたからもう最初からほぼ完璧で。
I knew it, so it was almost perfect right from the start.
いやいや、そんなことないですよ！ウチは「あわわ、あわわ」ってしてて。
No no, not at all! I was going "Awa wa, awa wa"!
めちゃくちゃ素敵なね、声の伸びだったよ。
Your voice had such a wonderful resonance.
なんかハモれてすごい楽しかった！ちょっと緊張したけど。
It was so fun harmonizing! Though I was a bit nervous.
かなりあきちゃんのね、ハーモニーに助けられたっていうか。
I was really saved by Aki-chan's harmonies.
やっぱハーモニーうまいからさ、あきちゃん。さすがあきちゃんだよね。まあ、うちはまだ精進させていただきますが。
Aki-chan, you're so good at harmonies. As expected of Aki-chan. Well, I still need to devote myself to improving.
じゃあ、そろそろあれですかね？
Well then, is it about time for that?
え！？え、まだ引っ張って！話すなら万々歳ですけど、万々歳始まっちゃう。
Eh?! Eh, still dragging it out? If we're talking it's great, but it'll start!
いや、まあそろそろね、次な、あの準備っていうことで、みおちゃんとあずきちゃんに歌ってもらうのね、あきちゃんはこっちの方に...
Well, as preparations for the next one, Mio-chan and Azuki-chan will sing, and Aki-chan...
ちょっとよろしいと
Just a moment, please.
がんばろうあずちゃん がんばろうで
Let's do our best, Az-chan. Let's do our best!
緊張するよ、ちょっ…
I'm so nervous, wait...
緊張するね
Me too.
うん
Yeah.
は、は、ここで覚えて
Ha, ha, remember here.
ちょっとお水飲もうかな
I think I'll drink some water.
お水飲んでね
Drink some water.
はい
Okay.
二人ともお水飲んでもらって
Both of you go drink some water.
じゃあ、その間に私ちょっとコメントを、あの、しようかな
Well, in the meantime, I'll go check some comments.
うんうんうんうん
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
いや、「くさ」っていう文字がすごく、あの、黄緑で目立って拾いやすいなったら
Man, the word "kusa" stands out so much in yellowish-green and is easy to pick up.
ああ、ですけど
Ah, that's true, but...
こっちがのが自作です
This one's homemade.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
そうです
Yep.
え、かわいい！スタンプ
Aah, cute stamp!
いや、でもね、こうやってみんなも、なんか、結構待ってたよ、ロサミアのライブ嬉しい！っていう声も、あの、見てたので
Man, but seeing everyone say "We've been waiting for RosaMiA's live, so happy!" made me so glad.
すごい、ありがとうございます
Thank you so much.
ちょっと緊張して、初挑戦なのでね、あの、色々と頑張る！っていうことでやってますので
I'm a bit nervous since it's our first time, so we're doing our best in various ways.
応援よろしくお願いします
We appreciate your support!
では、二人や準備できたみたいなので、次の曲聴いていただきましょう
Well, it looks like the two of them are ready, so let's listen to the next song.
夜光通信
"Yakou Tsuushin"
聞こえますか
Can you hear me?
夜の波よ 聞こえますか
Waves of the night, can you hear me?
そちは何年
Which year are you from?
新しく分かりあう手段は
A new way to truly understand each other
一つじゃないさ
is not just one.
漂う時間は どこへ行くのか
Where do drifting hours go?
さよならは いつ誰が決めるの
Who decides when it's time to say goodbye?
その手に触れようと願っている 本当さ
I truly hope to touch those hands...
永遠の夜よ 君に歌え 世界中が君に意地悪でも
Eternal night, I sing to you, even if the whole world is mean to you,
思い出して 覚えていて まぶたの裏 ずっとまた会えるからね
remember, keep it in mind, behind our eyelids we can meet again.
穏やかに 健やかに 奏でるブーケ 君だって私だって
Gracefully, healthily playing a bouquet, you and I alike,
消えるのは 言葉だけ
what vanishes are only words.
ふわり君を抱きしめてあげるからね 泣かないで
I'll softly embrace you, so don't cry.
延々と続く今日は 接ぎ木のようで
Days stretching endlessly seem like grafted branches.
突然の幸せまでも 狂わせるんだ
Even sudden happiness gets thrown into disorder.
どこでだって繋がる回線
Lines connecting us no matter where we are,
寂しい宇宙とオレンジの公園 下たしい心の鍵を歌おう
singing to the lonely universe and the orange park, with our close hearts' keys.
永遠の夜よ 届くよね
Eternal night, it will reach you, right?
幻想よりも優しい形のまま 濡れそぼるその方法を
Remaining in a form gentler than illusion, getting drenched, finding that way
こっそり撫でて乾かしてあげるからね 何度だって
I'll secretly stroke and dry you off, no matter how many times.
何度だって
No matter how many times.
永遠の夜よ 国中に歌え 会いたいよ 消えたくなかんてないよ
Eternal night, sing across the country, I want to see you, I don't want you to vanish.
思い出して 覚えていて 今ここで笑い合ったことを
Remember, keep it in mind, what we laughed about right here.
永遠の夜よ 君に歌え 世界中が君にいじわるでも
Eternal night, sing to you, even if the whole world is mean to you,
思い出して 覚えていて まぶたの裏 ずっとまた会えるからね さようならは
remember, keep it in mind, behind our eyelids we can meet again. Saying goodbye...
さようならは ねぇ 誰が決めるもの 消えるのは 言葉だけ
Saying goodbye, hey, who decides it? What vanishes are only words.
ふわり 君も 抱きしめてあげるからね
Gently, I'll hold you close as well,
泣かないで
so don't cry.
というわけで、
And so,
夜光通信 歌わせていただきましたー！
we sang "Yako Tsushin"!
夜光通信、ありがとうございますー！
Thank you so much for "Yako Tsushin"!
いやあ、すごくね、素敵にききっててたんですけど、
Man, it sounded so wonderful and nice, but...
あの、なんと 嬉しいお知らせがありまして、
we actually received some very happy news!
なんですか？
What is it?
あの トレンド1位を こちら初めて獲得しましたー！やったー！
We reached #1 on the trends for the very first time! Yay!
嬉しい！みんなのおかげ 世界におっかけ！
I'm so happy! Thanks to everyone, chasing the world!
ロサミアの名を届かせて…
Spreading ROSA MIA's name...
届かせて…嬉しいね！
Spreading it... We're so happy!
1位はみんなのにすごーい！嬉しい！ありがとうみんな！
#1 is amazing everyone! I'm so happy! Thank you everyone!
みんなのね、あのコメントでも、
Also, in everyone's comments,
アレンジが、そのアコースティックバージョン、すごい、いいっていうコメントもたくさんあったし、
many people said the acoustic arrangement is really good,
やっぱハーモニーがすごく綺麗ってすごいみんなね言ってくれてて、嬉しいな！
and that the harmony is so beautiful—everyone kept telling us that, I'm so glad!
でも上手にできたよね！できたよね！
But we did a great job, didn't we? We did!
うん、できた！できた！
Yeah, we did! We did!
なんかこう、迎え合ってさ、歌ってるとことかさ、
And when we faced each other and sang,
なんかぞくぞくしたもね。ぞくぞくした！
we got all kinds of chills. Chills!
まあ、実はですね、こちら選曲はあずちゃんがしてくれまして、
Well, actually, Azu-chan chose this song for us,
私、いや今回はみおちゃんの枠でアースティックさせて、
and I was allowed to do it in Mio-chan's frame,
ということもありせえつつながら、やはり、もうこの曲大好きすぎて、みおちゃんの、夜光通信を、
and while feeling a bit bashful, I love this song so much, Mio-chan's "Yako Tsushin",
なんか歌いマクっててですみません！
I'm sorry for singing it so much!
いやいやいや、嬉しいんですけどね、なんか本人よりも歌ってるという噂がある
No, no, no, we're happy, but there's a rumor you sing it more than the original artist!
なんか、あ、あずきちゃん、今日も歌ってる、あ、今日も歌ってるって、あずきちゃんも歌ってるって、めちゃ嬉しいんだけどね、本当に！ありがとうございます！
Like, "Oh, Azuki-chan is singing it today too!" We're so happy about that, truly! Thank you!
いやでもかなり、その、今回アコースティックアレンジで、より、曲のよさも、伝わったんじゃないかな？
But I feel like with this acoustic arrangement, the goodness of the song was conveyed even more!
え、もさがね、より強調されてたよね！歌詞も素敵でさ。
Yeah, Mosa, it was emphasized even more! The lyrics are wonderful too.
ああ、よかった、本当に！
Ah, I'm so glad, truly!
聞き惚れました。
I was mesmerized listening to it.
いや、よかったです。みんなよかったかな？どうでした？そう、お願いします。
Well, I'm glad. Was everyone happy? How was it? Please let us know.
はい、お願いします。じゃあ、ちょい、ちょい、ちょい、ちょい、言うことで…
Yes, please. So, um, speaking of which...
ここでね、いいにできたということは、あずちゃんとあきちゃんの、ふたりでやったんじゃないですか？
Since we did such a good job here, wasn't it done by Azu-chan and Aki-chan together?
やっちゃいます！やります！はい！
We'll do it! We will! Yes!
あ、ちょっとお水飲む。
Ah, let me drink some water.
あ、ちょっとね、この間にうちMCやるからさ。
Ah, right, while you do that, I'll do some MC.
はい、というわけで、狼王チャンネルの、狼王ミオです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes, so, I'm Ookami Mio from Ookami Mio Channel! Nice to meet you!
こんばんは！みおだよ！
Good evening! It's Mio!
うち、うち、うちだよ！狼王ミオだよ！
It's me, me, me! It's Ookami Mio!
これやってなかったからね。
I hadn't done this yet.
みんな可愛い！
Everyone is cute!
ありがとう！助かる。
Thank you! That helps.
休憩してないんだよな、あんまり。チャチャ入れてんだよな。
I haven't really taken a break. I keep chiming in.
はい、というわけでね、皆さんね、コメントいっぱいありがとうございます！そして、ロサミア アコースティックライブでね、
Yes, so everyone, thank you so much for all the comments! And at the ROSA MIA Acoustic Live,
あの、トレンド1位にもしていただいたということで、たくさんきっとタグもね、賑わっているでしょう！あとで感想見るの、めちゃ楽しみにしています！
we reached #1 on the trends, so I'm sure the tags are very lively! I'm really looking forward to reading your impressions later!
というわけで、準備もよさそうなので、
So, it looks like preparations are ready,
そろそろ聞いていただきましょうか、皆さん！
shall we have you listen soon, everyone?
では、皆さんの準備はいいですか？聞いていただきましょう。
Well, is everyone ready? Please listen.
「月のワルツ」
"Tsuki no Waltz"
ああ… ああ…
Ah... Ah...
はら はら はら はら はら…
Flutter, flutter, flutter...
こんなに月が青い夜は 不思議なことが起きるよ
On a night when the moon is this blue, something mysterious happens.
どこか深い森のなかで さまよう 私
Wandering somewhere deep within the forest, it is me.
タキシード姿の兎が来て
A rabbit in a tuxedo comes,
ワインわいかかと震え
trembling...
真っ赤なきのこの傘の下で 踊りが始まる
and under the shade of a bright red mushroom, the dance begins.
どこにいるの？
Where are you?
時間の国の迷子
Lost in a country of time.
帰り道がわからないの
I don't even know the way home.
待って待っているのに
Even though I'm waiting and waiting...
眠れるこの魂は あなたを探し森の中
This slumbering soul searches for you...
じゃんどらまはるのおじさまが 膝まずいてワルツりさそう
deep within the forest.
睫毛の長い蝶々達が シフォンのドレスひらひらと
Long-eared cicadas flutter in line,
虹色のタイツの兜の虫は 剣のダンス
and the beetle wears a rainbow breastplate, dancing with a sword.
求めるものは何？
What is it that you're searching for?
迷宮のラビリンス
A labyrinth of illusions,
ミルク色の霧の彼方
Milky-colored mist in the distance...
確かないかが欲しい
I'm sure I want love.
冷たいこの爪先を 白鳥の羽で跳ねてくんで
Dancing with the wings of a crane on my cold tiptoes.
じゃんどらまはるのおじさまは あなたに見た瞳ではねる
The gentleman of Chandramahar is looking at you with a single eye.
道手では分ける 空を行く
Roads will branch out as we cross the sky,
神秘の船
on a mysterious ship—
変わらないものなどないと
there's no such thing as change.
語りかけてくるよ
Whisper it to me and spin around.
こんなに月が青い夜は 不思議なことが起きるよ
Such a blue night is bound to bring strange things.
どこか見知らぬ森の中で 彷徨う私
Wandering deep within a forest unknown to anyone,
こんなに月が青い夜は 不思議なことが起きるよ
such a blue night is bound to bring strange things.
愛することは信じること
To love is to believe,
いつかその胸に抱かれ 眠った夢を見る
and one day, held in those arms, to see a sleepy dream.
そう いうことで 月のワルツでした
That's right, it's the Moon Waltz!
素晴らしかった！
That was wonderful!
大変だった！
It was so hard!
いや あのさ うちはさ やっぱ最初から
You know, for us, we've known each other since the very beginning,
2人が練習してる時から知ってるんだけど
when the two of us were practicing,
今日完成したかなって
and today we finally completed it!
えっ本当に？えっ嬉しい！
Really? I'm so happy!
本当に綺麗だった
It was so pretty.
声震え動くなった
My voice got shaky.
えっ嬉しい、やった！綺麗だった
I'm so glad we did it!
いや でもさ
Yeah, but you know,
緊張したよね なんか
we were so nervous, weren't we?
ハモリでさ 入るところがいつもドキドキするってさ あのお話ししててさ
We kept saying things like, "What if we mess up the harmonization?"
今回そう、あきちゃんメインで あずきがねハモリで入らせてもらっているんですけれども
And this time, Aki-chan is on melody and Azuki-chan is on harmony,
このハモリが
and this harmony—
いやめっちゃ練習したのよ
we practiced it so much!
確かにおい あーもう本当に偉いなっていう なんか感動しちゃった
Right, seriously, I'm so impressed.
成長したやっぱ素晴らしいなって
I grew so much!
いやいいハモリでしたね
It was such a good harmony!
ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
でもなんかここで満足しちゃいけませんよ
We shouldn't be satisfied with just this!
ここで満足しちゃダメ まだ早いですよ
We can't be satisfied yet, it's still early!
だってみんなでさ 1曲しか歌ってないから
There are only three of us and we've only sung one song!
確かに！えっ、ROSaMiAなのに
That's true! We're ROSaMiA, after all!
そうだよ、こっからね
That's right, from here on out!
みんなもまだまだ「えっもう？」 「次何？次何？」
Everyone's still like, "What, what's next?"
何でしょう？
What is it?
だってさ、なんか…なんだったんだろうね。
Because, you know... I wonder what that was.
いや本当にね、ステージもきれいで、なんかさっき…
Yeah, really, the stage is so beautiful, and just now...
なんか、なんかでもそうでしたでしょ？
Wait, wasn't it like that just now too?
そうなの。
That's right.
そうそうそうそう、あの…もう、い、今なくなっちゃったけどさ。
Yeah, yeah, like... wait, it just disappeared now.
でもね、ちゃんといてって、あの、今日も月がきれいですねって言ってくれてたから、コメントでも。
But you know, she stayed and said, "The moon is beautiful today, too," in the comments.
月のワルツ。
Waltz of the Moon.
あら！あのイメージで。
Oh! With that image.
そうなんです。月の破片に…もらってもらいまして。
That's right. We had you take us into... a fragment of the moon.
ここはなんか宇宙空間な感じなんですかね？宇宙空間？
Is this supposed to feel like outer space? Outer space?
うん、すごいステージだ。
Yeah, what an amazing stage.
きれいだな。きれいだな。
It's so beautiful. So beautiful.
じゃあちょっとね、そろそろ次の曲に行っちゃいます？
Well then, shall we move on to the next song soon?
行っちゃいますか？
Shall we?
え、もう行っちゃう？
Eh, already?
やばい、ちょっと緊張してお水…お水飲みたくなっちゃうかも。ちょっと、緊張してきた。
Oh no, I'm getting a bit nervous, I might want to drink some water... I've gotten so nervous.
緊張してきた。
I've gotten nervous.
大丈夫かな？
Will I be okay?
いや、次の曲も結構ね、あの…
Well, the next song also has quite a bit of...
気合がね、あるよね。
enthusiasm to it, right?
気合をしまして…
Gathering our spirit...
入ります。
Here we go.
気合入ります。
We're all fired up.
お！なんと、ステージがちょっと変わりまして…きれいだな。
Oh! What, the stage has changed a bit... How pretty.
このキューブはなんかちょっと懐かしくないですか？身覚えが…
Don't these cubes feel a bit nostalgic? Does it ring a bell...
身覚えがある！実は、アキロゼのセンター祭でふたりに来てもらって、あの、歌わせてもらった時…
It rings a bell! Actually, for Akirose's Center Festival, we had the two of you come over, and when we sang it...
最初、3人で歌わせてもらった時に、こうゆうなんかキューブ上のステージで歌わせてもらったんだけど、なんかそれをね、ちょっと彷彿とさせるっていう…
At first, when the three of us sang it on a stage made of these cube things, it kind of evoked that memory...
君の銀河には、そうね、歌ったという記憶があります。
We have the memory of singing it in your galaxy, right?
え、それ歌うんですか？えー、そんな！なんだろ、何歌うんだろ？
Eh, are you going to sing that? Eh, no way! I wonder what we're going to sing?
そんな、ね、思い出もありますけれど…そうなんですよ。
We have memories like that too, but... that's right.
実はね、まだ聴いてない人はよかったら、あの、聴いてみてください。そっちもすごく頑張ったんで。
Actually, if you haven't listened to it yet, please check it out. We worked really hard on that too.
チャンネルで上がってますね。そうなんです。
It's up on the channel. That's right.
そういうわけで、ここからなんと、2曲連続で歌っていきます！はい。ちょっと音を合わせさせてください、難しい曲なので。
And with that, from here on, we're going to sing two songs consecutively! Yes. Please let us get our pitch right, as it's a difficult song.
歌で始まりますからね。
Since it starts with vocals.
Everyday, I listen to my heart
ひとりじゃない
I am not alone.
深い胸の奥で繋がってる
Connected deep within my chest.
果てしない時を越えて、輝く星が出逢えた奇跡
Beyond endless time, the miracle of encountering shining stars.
教えてくれる、Everyday, I listen to my heart, ひとりじゃない
Teaches me, Everyday, I listen to my heart, I am not alone.
この空の胸に抱かれて
Held in the bosom of this sky.
Jupiter
私のこの両手で何ができるのだろう
What can I do with these two hands of mine?
痛みに触れさせて、そっと目を閉じて
Let me touch the pain, and gently close my eyes.
夢を失うよりも悲しいことは
More painful than losing a dream is
自分を信じてあげられないこと
Not being able to believe in oneself.
愛を学ぶために孤独があるなら
If solitude exists to teach us love,
あればいいのに
I wish it did.
ここにはいない…
You aren't here...
心の隅っこに 耳をすまして
Listen closely to the corner of your heart,
私を呼んだなら どこへでもゆくわ
If you call me, I'll go anywhere.
あなたのその涙 私のものに
I'll make your tears entirely my own...
今は自分を 抱きしめて
Right now, hold yourself close,
命のぬくもり 感じて
And feel the warmth of life.
私たちは誰も ひとりじゃない
None of us are ever truly alone.
ありのままでずっと 愛されてる
You are loved just as you are, always.
望むように生きて 輝く未来を
Live as you wish, toward a shining future,
いつまでも歌うわ あなたのために
I will sing on forever, for your sake.
ああ…
Ah...
いつまでも…
Forever...
私に還りなさい 記憶をたどり
Return to me, tracing your memory,
優しさと夢の水源へ もいちど星にひかれて 生まれるために
back to the source of gentleness and dreams, led once more by the stars to be born anew.
魂のルフラン
It's soul's refrain.
Soul's Refrain
蒼い影につつまれた素肌が ときの中で静かにふるえている
Your bare skin, wrapped in blue shadows, trembles quietly in the passage of time,
命の行方を問いかけるように 指先は私を求める
as if questioning the path of life, your fingertips seek me out.
抱きしめてた運命のあなたは 季節に咲くまるですてきな花はな
The destiny you held close is like a lovely flower blooming out of season—
希望のにおいを胸に残して 散り急ぐあざやかな姿で
leaving the scent of hope in my heart as you rush to scatter in vivid grace.
私に還りなさい 生まれる前に
Return to me, before your birth,
あなたが過ごした大地へと この腕に還りなさい めぐり逢うため
back to the earth where you once lived. Return to these arms, to meet again—
私に還りなさい 記憶をたどり
Return to me, tracing your memory,
私に還りなさい 生まれる前に
Return to me, before your birth,
あなたが過ごした 大地へと
to the earth where you spent your time,
この手に還りなさい めぐり逢うため
Return to my arms to meet again,
奇跡は起きるよ 何度でも 魂のルフラン
miracles will happen, time and time again—it's soul's refrain.
挑むようにまぶた閉じたときに
When I closed my eyes as if challenging,
世界はただ闇の底面に消える
the world simply vanishes into the depths of darkness.
それでもこの鼓動は また動き出す
Even so, this heartbeat starts to move once more,
限りある永遠を捜して
searching for a limited eternity.
私に還りなさい 記憶をたどり
Return to me, tracing your memory,
優しさと夢の水源へ
back to the source of gentleness and dreams,
あなたも還りなさい 愛し合うため
you too must return in order to love each other,
心も体もくりかえす
minds and bodies are repeated,
魂のルフラン
It's soul's refrain.
私に還りなさい 生まれる前に
Return to me, before your birth,
あなたが過ごした 大地へと
to the earth where you spent your time,
この手に還りなさい めぐり逢うため
Return to my arms to meet again,
奇跡は起きるよ 何度でも 魂のルフラン
miracles will happen, time and time again—it's soul's refrain.
ということで、はい、2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
And with that, yep, we performed two songs in a row!
わかってるよ、自分が一番わかってるよ...
I know, I know it best myself...
歌詞に触れちゃったら このまま話しちゃった
If I touch upon the lyrics, I'll just keep talking—
ちょっとやばい、これあきちゃんもしかして忘れてるかもと思って歌詞文字とか歌おうかなと思って一瞬迷ったんだけど
I thought Aki might have forgotten, so for a second I wondered if I should sing along with the lyrics...
でも途中で気づいたから、よかった！
but I realized halfway through, so thank goodness!
セーフ、セーフ、セーフ、セーフ！
Safe, safe, safe, safe!
みなさんすごいコメントの勢いが、物語ってますよ！すごい可愛かったよって言ってくれてるよ！
Everyone's comment momentum tells the story! They're saying it was super cute!
これが生の証明ですから！身を切って証明しちゃった
This is live proof! I proved it at my own expense—
完全体はね、成長コンテンツだからさ、一度もこういうの失敗したことない
Since the complete form is growth content, I've never failed like this before!
練習でも一度もなかったからびっくりした...
Even in practice it never happened once, so I was shocked...
本物の本物が来たんだもん！
Because the real deal arrived!
安心しちゃった後ろ見たら
I got too relieved and looked behind me—
全員後ろ向いてる...
Everyone's facing backwards...
恥ずかしくて火が出るかと思った
I thought my face was gonna catch fire from embarrassment!
まあでも、ここまでいっぱい練習した曲を披露できて嬉しいなって思ってるんですけど
Well, but, I'm happy we got to perform a song we practiced so much up to here—
ここでですね、うちからちょっとお知らせ、お知らせってみんな知ってるんですけど、なんと大神ミオ誕生日記念グッズ発売中でございます！
And here, an announcement from us—well, everyone already knows, but Ookami Mio's birthday celebration merchandise is on sale!
まずお知らせ、こちらチェックしてみてください！スカジャンとですね
First announcement, please check this out! A sukajan jacket and—
アクリルキーホルダーと、なっております！こちらですね、受注期間あと4日なので、お早めに！
and an acrylic keychain! The order period is only 4 days left, so please be quick!
「買い忘れてた！」って人はね、ちょっと早めに買って頂けると…
"For those who forgot to buy it..." please purchase it a bit early...
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
ていうわけで、まあ、さらっとね、お知らせしちゃったんですけど、はい。
So, well, I casually made that announcement, but yes.
もう一個ありますよね？ サムネイルに予告ありって。
There's another thing, right? It was teased in the thumbnail.
あ、そう！予告ありましたけど、今日は3人の告知が、
Ah, right! There was a teaser, but today the three of us have
なんと、なんです？ なんですか？ いいですか、言っちゃって？
an announcement... what is it? May I say it?
なんと！ロサミアのファーストシングルがデジタルリリースされます！
And so! RosaMiA's 1st single will be digitally released!
タイトル「Blossom Sinfonia」でございます！
The title is "Blossom Sinfonia"!
オリジナル楽曲ですね！オリジナル楽曲なんですよ、なんと！
It's an original song! It really is an original song, oh!
我らロサミアのファーストシングルということで、ま、初めに相応しいような、
As RosaMiA's first single, a song fitting for the beginning,
3人の声が咲き誇るような、楽曲に
where our three voices bloom in full glory—
そして我らのロサミアロードも、咲き誇ってくれるように
designed so that our RosaMiA road will also bloom bright,
大事に育てていきたいなと思ってる楽曲ですし、みんなにも愛される曲に
a song we want to cherish and watch grow, and hope becomes beloved by all,
このあと24時から、各配信サイトでダウンロードできますので、ぜひ聴いてくださいね！
so from midnight tonight you can download it on streaming sites, please listen!
ていうわけで、で、ま、でもこの曲どんな曲か気になるー！
So, well... but we're curious about what kind of song this is!
気になるよね！イメージ出るようなのだけ教えてね。
We are! Give us just an idea of what kind of song it is.
華やかなのか？難易度高いのか？わかる、わかんないかなあって。
Is it gorgeous? Is it high difficulty? I wonder if we can tell...
みんな聴きたいよね！聴きたい聴きたい！
Everyone wants to hear it, right? We want to hear it!
あの、みんなのコメントを読んでいます。ちょっと、その間に水飲むよ。
Um, we're reading everyone's comments. I'll drink some water in the meantime.
イラストもいい、ビジュアルもいい、ありがとう！気になる、マジで！
Illustration is good, visuals are good, thank you! Super curious!
あの、え、Hololiveさん、どうですか？ 滅茶苦茶どうですか？
Hololive-san, how is it? What is it like?
ということでね、なんとあずちゃんこの後お披露目しちゃうかもしれない。
So, Azu-chan might reveal something right after this!
これ、は最後まで見逃せないってこと？
Does that mean we can't miss a single second until the very end?
なんとこのあと生歌唱にて初お披露目させていただきます！ハードル高い！
We will perform it live for the first time right after this! The hurdle is high!
この曲歌唱難易度がバッチ高くてですね、一番の最難関歌となっております。
This song has exceptionally high vocal difficulty, the most challenging song yet.
この曲一番最初に練習し始めたもんで、どの曲よりも練習したけど難しい。
Since we practiced this song first, we practiced it more than any other, yet it's hard.
これを聴いてね、なんかこういうハモリとか好きな人もいると思うからさ。
When you hear this, we think there are people who like harmonies like this.
待ってます。じゃあ、えっと、こちら今日本日24時、あ、明日24時？
We're waiting. So, um, today at 24:00—tomorrow at 24:00?
このあとデジタルリリースされる曲となります。
It's a song that will be digitally released right after this.
もういいですか、いっちゃって？ちょっと、順番があるんでしょ？
Is it okay to say it? Wait, there's an order, right?
大丈夫？あきろぜは、大丈夫じゃないよ！
Are you okay? Akirose is not okay!
うそでしょ？ちょっと、大丈夫だろうよ、頑張って！心配しないでね。
No way? Come on, you'll be fine, do your best! Don't worry.
今までの練習の成果を発揮すればええねん！練習してきたもん！
Just show the results of your practice so far! You've practiced!
それでは聴いてください。「Blossom Sinfonia」！
Well then, please listen. "Blossom Sinfonia"!
遠くのあなたに 歌届くように
So my song reaches you far away...
今宵に怯える 私がいる
There is a part of me trembling in tonight,
それでも 明日に 期待している
yet I am still looking forward to tomorrow.
あの日に見つけた 奇跡の種
The miraculous seed I found on that day...
いつでも そこには
No matter what, always
希望がある
hope is right there.
暗くても
Even in the darkness,
一筋さす
a single beam shines through
明日への光へと
toward tomorrow's light,
手を伸ばしてる
reaching out our hands—
今でも
even now.
途切れないように 繋いできたから
Connected so it wouldn't break, since we've kept it going,
今 目覚め始めた 未来があるの
now there's a newly awakened future waiting for us.
遠くのあなたに 歌が届くように
So our song can reach you far away,
この先も紡ぐの
we will keep weaving it into the future.
大事に抱えた 希望の芽は
The sprouts of hope we held so dear,
儚く儚い それでもいい
fleeting as they are, that's fine—
いつのか 小さくても
no matter how small they may be,
重なれば鮮やかに染め上げられる 世界を
if they overlap, they can dye the world brightly.
信じた未来へ 歩いてきたから
Walking toward the future we believed in,
今 手を取り合える 仲間がいるの
now we have friends whose hands we can hold.
遠くのあなたの 手を握れるように
So we can hold your hand far away,
花は今覗く
the flowers are now peeking through.
不安でも
Even if we're uneasy,
大丈夫と くじけても 続けてきた
telling ourselves it's okay, even when discouraged, we kept going.
弱くても 怖くてもいい
It's okay to be weak, it's okay to be scared.
開けるときめて 巡り合えたあなたへ
To you, whom we decided to open up to and met—
途切れないように 繋いできたから
Connected so it wouldn't break, since we've kept it going,
今 鮮やかなほど 咲き誇る花
now flowers bloom as brilliantly as ever.
遠くのあなたに 歌が届くように
So our song reaches you far away,
変わらないよ ずっと何があっても ずっとあなたへと 紡ぐの
it won't change, no matter what happens, we'll keep weaving it toward you forever.
本日24時よりデジタルリリース！ぜひみんなロサミアのファーストシングル聞いてね！
Digital release tonight at midnight! Be sure to listen to RosaMIA's first single!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
告知あり
[Announcement]